<tips lang="English">
  <tip author="Jimi Hendrix">You can't mess with people's heads, that's for sure. But that's what music's all about, messing with people's heads.</tip>
  <tip author="Oscar Wilde">If one hears bad music, it is one's duty to drown it by one's conversation.</tip>
  <tip author="Queen Elisabeth II">I know the song and I can make all those noises at home.</tip>
  <tip author="Josef Hofmann ">Music is the most expensive of all noises.</tip>
  <tip author="Samuel Johnson">Of all noises, I think music is the least disagreeable.</tip>
  <tip author="Patrick Murray">Modern music is just noise with attitude.</tip>
  <tip author="Dave Edmunds">There'll always be some arrogant little brat who wants to make music with a guitar. Rock'n'roll will never die.</tip>
  <tip author="Miguel de Unamuno">Slave drivers know well enough that when the slave is singing a hymn to liberty he is consoling himself for his slavery and not thinking about breaking his chain.</tip>
  <tip author="Eduard Hanslick">The other arts persuade us, but music takes us by surprise.</tip>
  <tip author="Samuel Pepys">Music and women I cannot but give way to, whatever my business is.</tip>
  <tip author="Joseph Haydn in old age">Musical ideas pursue me to the point of torture. I cannot get rid of them, they stand before me like a wall. If it is an allegro that pursues me, my pulse beats faster, I cannot sleep; if an adagio, I find my pulse beating slowly. My imagination plays upon me as if I were a keyboard.</tip>
  <tip author="Jukka Pekka Saraste">A music listener is like a fish that swallows a bait. If you are hooked, you can no longer do anything, you must finish the process.</tip>
  <tip author="Rafael Ramstedt">There are tunes, that cling to us like dirt on an old piece of furniture.</tip>
  <tip author="Plato, Taurus">Philosophy is the highest music.  </tip>
  <tip author="Quentin Crisp, Capricorn">Long ago I said that all the harm that had come to the world was due to the music, and now someone has arisen and said there will be no more concerts in Central Park because everybody behaved so badly. It seems to me self-evident: All you have to do to restore order to the world is to stop the music. It will mean people will start to speak.</tip>
  <tip author="Ralph Waldo Emerson, Gemini">The music that can deepest reach, And cure all ill, is cordial speech.</tip>
  <tip author="Oliver Herford. Sagittarius">Song: the licensed medium for bawling in public things too silly or sacred to be uttered in ordinary speech.  </tip>
  <tip author="Sir John Hawkins on Samuel Johnson">Of music in general he has been heard to say, 'it excites in my mind no ideas, and hinders me from contemplating my own.</tip>
  <tip author="Roger North">Music hath two ends, first to please the sense... and secondly to move the affections or excite passion... And it must be granted that pure impulse artificially acted and continued hath great power to excite men to act but not to think... The melody is only to add to the diversion.</tip>
  <tip author="Peter York">Rock and roll is the hamburger that ate the world.</tip>
  <tip author="Frank Sinatra">Sagittarius Rock 'n Roll: The most brutal, ugly, desperate, vicious form of expression it has been my misfortune to hear.</tip>
  <tip author="Billy Corgan">I don't believe in god. I don't believe in America. I don't believe in rock and roll. All I believe in is me.</tip>
  <tip author="John Ruskin">If the music be right, the poem may be insipid or inharmonious, and still saved by the notes to which it is wedded. But this is far more true of colour. If that be wrong, all is wrong.</tip>
  <tip author="Paul Verlaine">Music before everything else ... Music again and forever!</tip>
  <tip author="Billy Joel">Music ... is something we are all touched by. No matter what culture we're from, everyone loves music.</tip>
  <tip author="G. K. Chesterton">Life exists for the love of music or beautiful things.</tip>
  <tip author="Thomas de Quincey">Music is an intellectual or sensual pleasure, according to the temperament of him who hears it.</tip>
  <tip author="Samuel Johnson">Music is the only sensual pleasure without vice. </tip>
  <tip author="Confucius">Music produces a kind of pleasure which human nature cannot do without.</tip>
  <tip author="Martin Luther">My heart, which is so full to overflowing, has often been solaced and refreshed by music when sick and weary.</tip>
  <tip author="Frank Zappa">Intelligence is not knowledge, knowledge is not wisdom, wisdom is not truth, truth is not beauty, beauty is not love, love is not music. Music is best.</tip>
  <tip author="Albert Schweitzer">There are two means of refuge from the misery of life, music and cats.</tip>
  <tip author="John Ruskin">Music is the nearest at hand, the most orderly, the most delicate, and the most perfect, of all bodily pleasures; it is also the only one which is equally helpful to all the ages of man.</tip>
  <tip author="Gioacchino Rossini">Every kind of music is good, except the boring kind.</tip>
</tips>

<tips lang="Russian">
  <tip author="Бетховен">Ваша опера мне понравилась. Пожалуй, я напишу к ней музыку.</tip>
  <tip author="Михаил Генин">Так и не довелось мне поплясать под чужую дудку: все что-то не устраивало - то музыка, то инструмент, то исполнитель...</tip>
  <tip author="Стив Мартин">Говорить о музыке - все равно что танцевать об архитектуре.</tip>
  <tip author="Фридрих Ницше">Без музыки жизнь была бы ошибкой.</tip>
  <tip author="Генрих Нейгауз">Звук должен быть окутан тишиной.</tip>
  <tip author="Генри Уорд Бичер">Из всей земной музыки ближе всего к небесам - биение истинно любящего сердца.</tip>
  <tip author="Ж.-П. Рихтер">Из всех искусств музыка - самое человечное и распространенное. </tip>
  <tip author="Бертольд Ауэрбах">Музыка - единственный всемирный язык, его не надо переводить, на нем душа говорит с душою.</tip>
  <tip author="Ф. Шопен ">Музыка не имеет отечества; отечество ее - вся вселенная. </tip>
  <tip author="Л. Бетховен">Музыка должна высекать огонь из людских сердец.</tip>
  <tip author="Л. Бетховен">Музыка - посредница между жизнью ума и жизнью чувств. </tip>
  <tip author="И. Эренбург">Музыка, не упоминая ни о чем, может сказать все.</tip>
  <tip author="Стендаль">Музыка, когда она совершенна, приводит сердце в точно такое же состояние, какое испытываешь, наслаждаясь присутствием любимого существа, то есть, что она дает, несомненно, самое яркое счастье, какое только возможно на земле.</tip>
  <tip author="Антони Берджесс">Музыка ничего не говорит разуму: это идеально структурированная бессмыслица.</tip>
  <tip author="Теодор Адорно">Не мы слушаем музыку, а музыка слушает нас. </tip>
  <tip author="Тадеуш Котарбиньский">Музыка — это искусство печалить и радовать без причины.</tip>
  <tip author="Кшиштоф Билица">Музыка облагораживает нравы, но нравы развращают музыку.</tip>
  <tip author="Карл Барт">Не знаю, в самом ли деле ангелы в присутствии Бога играют лишь Баха; но я уверен, что в своем домашнем кругу они играют Моцарта.</tip>
  <tip author="Фридрих Ницше">Нужны новые уши для новой музыки.</tip>
</tips>
